<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>MicroAlchemy Blog</title>
    <link>https://microalchemy.xyz/blog</link>
    <description>Build logs, architecture notes, and experiments from the MicroAlchemy team.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 09:53:37 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microalchemy Primer</title>
      <link>https://microalchemy.xyz/blog/primer</link>
      <guid>https://microalchemy.xyz/blog/primer</guid>
      <description>Why we are compressing silicon prototyping timelines and how we plan to ship it.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1>MicroAlchemy Primer</h1>
<p>We&#x27;re building tools and collapse the distance between an idea and working silicon. The goal is
simple: <strong>cut fabrication lead times to weeks</strong> so teams can iterate as fast on silicon as they do on code.</p>
<div class="callout callout-info"><div class="callout-header">What we are shipping</div><div class="callout-body"><p>Wafers in under three weeks, an open-source analog-first design stack (Alembic), and an ecosystem that
keeps the tooling, simulation, and fabrication loop tight.</p></div></div>
<h2>Design loops should be shorter</h2>
<ul>
<li>Traditional foundries are focused on pushing the economics per transistor rather than design speed
<ul>
<li>It can take anywhere from three months to a full year to go from a finalized design to a chip in hand at today’s foundries</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Analog design is still artisanal; we are raising the abstraction with Alembic.</li>
<li>Tooling wants to be open; community contributions unlock better models and flows.</li>
</ul>
<h2>How we approach the stack</h2>
<ol>
<li><strong>Language-first</strong>: Alembic expresses analog intent without drowning in device minutiae.</li>
<li><strong>Tight simulation</strong>: We validate designs against the exact stack we fab on—no surprises at tapeout.</li>
<li><strong>Fast fab</strong>: Our process targets a 1μm node with reliable turnaround for experiments and MVP silicon.</li>
</ol>
<div class="callout callout-success"><div class="callout-header">Win</div><div class="callout-body"><p>You will see progress logs, benchmarks, and build breakdowns here. If you want to collaborate or test on
our pipeline, email aditya@microalchemy.xyz</p></div></div>]]></content:encoded>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
